The inside story of the painting that seduced the world.
The Lost Leonardo is a documentary, history film directed by Andreas Koefoed.
London, England, 2008.
Some of the most distinguished experts on the work of Italian artist Leonardo da Vinci (1452-1519) gather at the National Gallery to examine a
painting known as Salvator Mundi; an event that turns out to be the first act of one of the most fascinating stories in the history of art.
Self - Writer and Journalist, played by Georgina Adam.
Self - Art Dealer, played by Warren Adelson.
Self - Banker, played by Evan Beard.
Self - Freeport Owner and Businessman, played by Yves Bouvier.
Self - Writer, played by Alexandra Bregman.
Self - Editor, played by Alison Cole.
The Lost Leonardo is an internationally co-produced documentary
film directed by Andreas Koefoed, released in 2021.
It follows the discovery and successive sales of the painting the Salvator Mundi, allegedly a work by
Leonardo da Vinci, an artist for whom there are only a few attributed works in existence.
The film chronicles the dramatic increases in the painting's value from its original purchase in 2005 for $1,175
to its auction in 2017 for $450 million, when it became the most expensive artwork ever sold.
The use of high-end artwork for hiding wealth, as well as the conflicts created by
large commissions and other economic incentives, are explored in the film.
It includes interviews with leading art experts and art critics on issues
regarding the provenance and authenticity of the work.
Production was announced in late 2019 following the success of Ben Lewis's book The
Last Leonardo: The Secret Lives of the World’s Most Expensive Painting.
The film had its world premiere at the Tribeca Film Festival on June 13, 2021, and was released in the United States on
August 13, 2021, by Sony Pictures Classics and in the United Kingdom on September 10, 2021, by Dogwoof.
The film was widely praised by critics for its content, pacing
and the portrayal of the subject as a thriller.
A French-made film on the topic called The Saviour for
Sale was also released at the same time.
In October 2022, StudioCanal announced a plan to develop the film into a
limited series with The Picture Company and Entertainment360.
The film explores themes of painting, leonardo da vinci,
based on true story, art, art auction.